{
  "q1": [
    {
      "question": "This man signed a deed in which Philip Ford gained control of his territories. He limited capital punishment to murder and treason in the Frame of Government. According to tradition, this man promised, under the Great Elm, “perpetual friendship” with the Lenni Lenape at Shackamaxon. He laid out 5 public squares for a city between the Schuylkill (pr. \"school\" \"kill\") and Delaware Rivers. For 10 points, name this Quaker who founded a namesake colony containing Philadelphia.",
      "answer": "William Penn <CW> {II}"
    },
    {
      "question": "At a 2015 sporting event in this country, Iranian women unveiled a banner depicting a woman who was arrested for trying to enter a volleyball match. The 2014 G20 Summit was held in this country. Following that summit, several world leaders’ personal details were leaked to the organizers of the 2015 Asian Cup, which took place in this country. For 10 points, name this country where security was tightened following a December 2014 hostage-taking in Sydney.",
      "answer": "Commonwealth of Australia <KG> {III}"
    },
    {
      "question": "This product was stored in a large container found in the grave of the Lady of Vix. Domitian ordered that Italian production of this good be cut in half. This product was flung at a wall in a game called kottabos. This product was kept in kraters for use during symposiums. Pliny the Elder coined a phrase claiming that there is truth in this substance. For 10 point, name this commodity popular in ancient Greece and Rome which is made from fermented grapes.",
      "answer": "wine <JB> {II}"
    },
    {
      "question": "A controversy surrounding this substance led to the Kefauver-Harris Amendment. This substance was promoted by Chemie Grunenthal, and is used in Brazil to treat leprosy. This substance is composed of two enantiomers, one of which is responsible for adverse effects like phocomelia. This substance was meant to treat morning sickness in pregnant women. For 10 points, name this drug that caused a surge in birth defects in the late 1950s and early 1960s.",
      "answer": "Thalidomide <KG> {III}"
    },
    {
      "question": "A part of this building lent its name to the 1839 Supreme Edict of the Rose Chamber. This place's name literally means \"gate of cannons.\" The head of a regime often called the \"Sublime Porte\" primarily used this building, which contains Gülhane Park. After a 1574 fire, the architect Sinan helped rebuild this four-courtyard building complex, which sits on a hill called Seraglio Point. For 10 points, name this Istanbul building, the primary residential palace of the Ottoman sultan.",
      "answer": "Topkapi Palace <MJ> {III} 2015 National History Bowl High School Championships Round 14"
    },
    {
      "question": "Governor \"Pappy\" O'Daniel was the only man to beat this person in a race for elected office. This man used a helicopter called the \"City Windmill\" to take on Coke Stevenson in one race. John Connally was this man's campaign manager in a race that he won by 87 votes, giving him the nickname \"Landslide.\" For 10 points, name this man who won a controversial 1948 Senate primary race in Texas years before he became President of the United States.",
      "answer": "Lyndon Baines Johnson <MC> {III}"
    },
    {
      "question": "This man’s first major project was called the Grand Cross. This man’s immediate boss was the Duke of Persigny. Visits to London led this man to build many public parks and botanical gardens, including the Boulogne Woods. This man’s widening of streets was allegedly intended to make it difficult for rebels to set up barricades. For 10 points name this French baron who created many open boulevards during his redesign of Paris in the 1850’s and 60’s.",
      "answer": "Baron Georges-Eugene Haussman <BA> {III}"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first of these measures was the third of a set of resolutions introduced by Henry Pinckney. This resolution resulted in the censuring of Joshua Giddings due to the Creole case, and it became a standing rule with the passage of the Twenty-first Rule. John Quincy Adams finally secured the 1844 repeal of this measure, which immediately tabled certain documents. For 10 points, name this Congressional rule which barred the introduction of petitions related to slavery.",
      "answer": "Gag Rule <JZ> {III}"
    },
    {
      "question": "This athlete fleshed out his political viewpoints in the book I Have Changed. This athlete's endorsement of Adidas founder Adi Dassler's shoes helped jumpstart that company. He was forced to ride a freight elevator to a reception in his honor at the Waldorf-Astoria Hotel. This athlete denied that Adolf Hitler chose to snub him. For 10 points, name this African American who won four gold medals at the 1936 Berlin Summer Olympics.",
      "answer": "James “Jesse” Owens <MC> {III}"
    },
    {
      "question": "Angela Davis claimed that this woman wanted \"to exterminate the Negro population.\" She founded a newsletter called The Woman Rebel, whose slogan was \"No Gods, No Masters.\" This person wrote a regular column called \"What Every Girl Should Know\" for a New York newspaper. This woman founded the group that evolved into Planned Parenthood. For 10 points, name this woman who opened the first birth control clinic in the United States.",
      "answer": "Margaret Sanger <MC> {III}"
    },
    {
      "question": "The \"red\" city of Cleopolis is run by this literary figure. In the original plan for an unfinished poem, this person was to hold a twelve-day feast. This largely-unseen character is the boss of Sir Guyon, who smashes the Bower of Bliss. Prince Arthur has a full vision of this leader, who sends a warrior to defeat a dragon threatening the parents of Una. For 10 points, name this analogue of Queen Elizabeth I whom the Redcrosse Knight serves in Edmund Spenser's The Faerie Queene.",
      "answer": "Gloriana <MJ> {III} 2015 National History Bowl High School Championships Round 14"
    },
    {
      "question": "This sect initiated clerics through its only sacrament, called consolamentum. The highest rank in this sect was called “parfait” and required strict vegetarianism. Their theology, perhaps inspired by the earlier Paulicians and Bogomils, held that the physical world was evil and created by Satan. Raymond of Toulouse was among the nobles to seize land when Innocent III declared a crusade against them. For 10 points, name this dualistic Christian sect of southern France.",
      "answer": [
        "Cathars",
        "Albigensians <BA> {III} 2015 National History Bowl High School Championships Round 14"
      ]
    }
  ],
  "q2": [
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "After this king’s dying wife asked him to remarry, he responded “No, I will have mistresses!” This king’s wife Caroline of Ansbach was a supporter of Robert Walpole, who served as Prime Minister for the first 15 years of this man’s reign. His son the Duke of Cumberland defeated Bonnie Prince Charlie at Culloden and he was the last British monarch to lead forces in battle. For 10 points, which Hanoverian king of Great Britain ruled during the Seven Years War?",
        "answer": "George II of Great Britain"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "George II was the last British king to reside in what palace in London originally built by Cardinal Wolsey?",
        "answer": "Hampton Court Palace <TR> {III}"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "In one trial, this man was defended by George Williams and prosecuted by no one. An action against this man was justified in a letter by Edward Bates. George Cadwalader detained this man under suspicion of raising arms for rebellion against the Union, which led to the unsuccessful intervention by the sitting Chief Justice. For 10 points, name this Maryland man whose right of habeus corpus was the center of a writ issued by Roger Taney.",
        "answer": "John Merryman"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Habeus Corpus was also suspended under the third of what series of laws that ensured the implementation of the 14th and 15th Amendments during Reconstruction?",
        "answer": "Enforcement Acts <VP> {III}"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Following one defeat, corpses of these people were looted for items to send back \"to the ladies of Tennessee.\" At a climactic battle, John Coffee's forces prevented this tribe from escaping via the Tallapoosa River. This tribe lost a war that had begun with the Battle of Burnt Corn. Following Menawa's defeat, their chief William Weatherford surrendered at Fort Jackson. For 10 points, name this tribe of what's now Alabama whose Red Stick faction lost at Horseshoe Bend to Andrew Jackson.",
        "answer": "Creek tribe"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "What future national leader was wounded two separate times, once by an arrow and once by gunshot, during the Battle of Horseshoe Bend?",
        "answer": "Sam Houston <DW> {III}"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This band is the main focus of a film featuring a clip of Jefferson Airplane singer Marty Balin getting knocked out. During a performance by this band, Meredith Hunter was killed by the Hell’s Angels who were working security. Its disastrous performance at the 1969 Altamont Free Concert is the subject of the documentary Gimme Shelter, which has footage of them performing \"Sympathy for the Devil.\" For 10 points, name this rock band led by Mick Jagger.",
        "answer": "The Rolling Stones"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "What Jerry Garcia led rock band refused to play at Altamont after hearing about the attack on Marty Balin?",
        "answer": "The Grateful Dead <MC> {II} <CW> {III} 2015 National History Bowl High School Championships Round 14"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "One participant in this event called a different participant “half militarist half gangster.” The instigators of this event vowed not to pass a poisoned chalice to the defendants, who would be judged by Francis Biddle. This event was criticized by Harlan Fiske Stone as a “lynching party.” This event was authorized by the London Charter and led to the death of Hermann Goering and others. For 10 points, name this tribunal which tried leading Nazis for war crimes.",
        "answer": "Nuremburg trials"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "What Supreme Court Justice was the chief American prosecutor at the Nuremburg War Crimes Tribunal?",
        "answer": "Robert H. Jackson <JZ> {III}"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "One leader of this people won a battle after tossing away his helmet and charging the enemy, shouting “Oh my Islam!” These people were led by Aybak, who married Sultana Shajar al-Durr. They revolted against the Ayyubid dynasty and fought a battle where Kitbuqa was defeated by Qutuz. These people stopped the invasion of the Golden Horde at the Battle of Ain Jalut after Hulegu was recalled home. For 10 points, name these former slaves who ruled Egypt.",
        "answer": "Mamluks"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "What Mamluk leader led the vanguard at Ain Jalut and succeeded Qutuz after he was assassinated?",
        "answer": "Baibars <JZ> {III}"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "The creation of this doctrine was spurred by concerns about a phenomenon called \"declension.\" This doctrine amended Chapter XII of the Cambridge Platform and was championed by Solomon Stoddard. This doctrine arose from the decreasing number of \"Visible Saints,\" people who reported conversion experiences. For 10 points, name this reform in Puritan New England which allowed the children of partial church members to be baptized.",
        "answer": "Half-Way Covenant"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "What minister initially opposed the Half-Way Covenant and graduated from Harvard in 1656 before later becoming its president?",
        "answer": "Increase Mather <JB> {II}"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "In one work, this man states that “associations of ideas” made in infancy have a more lasting effect than associations made at maturity. While a secretary to the Earl of Shaftsbury, this man created a document which called for laws to expire after 100 years. This author of Some Thoughts Concerning Education and the Fundamental Constitution of Carolina posited that that civil society began with the creation of private property. For 10 points, name this author of the Two Treatises of Government.",
        "answer": "John Locke"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Locke’s name is sometimes written together with the post-nominal letters FRS, which denote that he belonged to which organization?",
        "answer": "Fellow of the Royal Society<EM> {II} 2015 National History Bowl High School Championships Round 14"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "A woman named Locusta created these things for Emperor Nero. La Voisin was accused of selling these things in a French affair named for them. Mithridates VI of Pontus was known for consuming small amounts of these things. Lucrezia Borgia allegedly used a ring that contained this sort of thing. During the Black Death, Jews were believed to have put this sort of substance in wells. For 10 points, name this type of substance exemplified by arsenic and cyanide.",
        "answer": "poisons"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "What expatriate former member of the Russian security services was assassinated by polonium poisoning in London in 2006?",
        "answer": "Alexander Litvinenko <JB> {II}"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This man ordered that public swimming pools be kept cold in the belief it would keep black people away. Fiorello LaGuardia kept a pre-printed pad of resignation letters for this man. He deliberately kept overpasses too low for buses to use the Wantagh Parkway and other roads he built on Long Island. For 10 points, name this subject of Robert Caro’s The Power Broker, who built the Verrazano Narrows Bridge and Cross Bronx Expressway?",
        "answer": "Robert Moses"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Moses’s planned Lower Manhattan Expressway was prevented by a coalition led by what author of The Death and Life of Great American Cities?",
        "answer": "Jane Jacobs <CW> {III}"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "One object used in this practice was known as the terebra. Bart Huges revived modern interest in this technique with the 1964 publication of \"Homo Sapiens Correctus.\" Although in some cultures the roundel created by this process may have served a religious purpose, Paul Broca hypothesized that it was performed to relieve pressure. Hippocrates described this technique in \"On the Injuries of the Head.\" For 10 points, what early method of surgery involved drilling a hole in the patient's skull?",
        "answer": "trepanning"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "What pre-Columbian culture, along with its predecessor Chimu and Moche cultures, performed trepanning with a ceremonial knife known as a tumi?",
        "answer": "Inca <DW> {III}"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This government hired 300 “lash bearers.” Lysias escaped from this government, which chose three thousand people to share in their regime. Thrasybulus led a revolt against this regime which culminated at the Battle of Piraeus. One leader of it, Theramenes, was killed on the orders of its most prominent member, Critias, who was tutored by Socrates. For 10 points, name this group of people who were installed as rulers of Athens by Sparta after the Peloponnesian War.",
        "answer": "Thirty Tyrants"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "What tyrant of Halicarnassus was a female commander at the Battle of Salamis for Xerxes I?",
        "answer": "Artemisia I of Caria <JZ> {III} 2015 National History Bowl High School Championships Round 14"
      }
    }
  ],
  "q3": [
    {
      "category": "THE 2008 U.S. PRESIDENTIAL ELECTION",
      "prompt": "In or around the United States presidential election season of 2008, what…",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Illinois senator promised \"Change we can believe in?\"",
          "answer": "Barack Hussein Obama II"
        },
        {
          "question": "state was home to candidates Mike Gravel and Sarah Palin?",
          "answer": "Alaska"
        },
        {
          "question": "city hosted the Democratic National Convention at Invesco Field?",
          "answer": "Denver, Colorado"
        },
        {
          "question": "barrier was said to have \"18 million cracks\" in Hillary Clinton's concession speech?",
          "answer": "glass ceiling"
        },
        {
          "question": "day featured 24 states' primaries and caucuses?",
          "answer": "Super Tuesday"
        },
        {
          "question": "tell-all book by John Heilemann and Mark Halperin gave a blow-by-blow of the race?",
          "answer": "Game Change: Obama and the Clintons, McCain and Palin, and the Race of a Lifetime"
        },
        {
          "question": "black Reverend became a campaign issue for speeches he made in the 80s?",
          "answer": "Reverend Jeremiah Wright"
        },
        {
          "question": "DNC attendees were free to nominate any candidate regardless of state primary results?",
          "answer": "superdelegates <MJ> {III}"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "AMSTERDAM",
      "prompt": "Name the amsterdam...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Has what manmade waterways crisscrossing throughout the city?",
          "answer": "canals"
        },
        {
          "question": "Was where what company was founded to manage interests in Southeast Asia?",
          "answer": "Dutch East India Company"
        },
        {
          "question": "Art museum re-opened in 2013 after a ten-year renovation?",
          "answer": "Rijksmuseum"
        },
        {
          "question": "Ran on what currency from the 1600’s until the adoption of the Euro?",
          "answer": "guilders"
        },
        {
          "question": "Has some of the earliest distilleries that make this beverage from juniper berries?",
          "answer": "gin"
        },
        {
          "question": "Has what town square in its center with the Royal Palace lying along its side?",
          "answer": "Dam Square"
        },
        {
          "question": "Was where what republic was established from 1795 to 1806 by a French intervention?",
          "answer": "Batavian Republic"
        },
        {
          "question": "Were controlled by what executive officers drawn from the nobility?",
          "answer": "stadtholders <VP> {III}"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "SIGMUND FREUD",
      "prompt": "Name the sigmund freud...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "is the \"father\" of what study of the unconscious mind?",
          "answer": "psychoanalysis"
        },
        {
          "question": "treated patients in what German-speaking capital city?",
          "answer": "Vienna, Austria"
        },
        {
          "question": "became popular treating victims of what World War I veterans' ailment?",
          "answer": "shell shock"
        },
        {
          "question": "was born in Moravia in which present-day country?",
          "answer": "Czech Republic"
        },
        {
          "question": "contrasted what term for societal development with its Discontents?",
          "answer": "civilization"
        },
        {
          "question": "inspired a \"school\" of critical theorists in what German hometown of J.W. von Goethe?",
          "answer": "Frankfurt"
        },
        {
          "question": "died in which city, where you can still see his famous couch?",
          "answer": "London"
        },
        {
          "question": "studied what disorders, in which a neurosis causes loss of a sense like sight?",
          "answer": "conversion disorders <MJ> {III}"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  "q4": [
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) In response to one of these events, the Pomgol committee was created by Patriarch Tikhon. An \"unknown\" one of these events was the subject of a Jonathan Dimbleby documentary that helped cause a 1973 coup. Amartya Sen attributes these events to (20 pts)",
        "distribution problems in an essay on \"Poverty\" and these events. One of these events in Ethiopia's Wollo province led Bob Geldof to organize the (10 pts)",
        "Live Aid concert. Many kulaks died in one of these events possibly aggravated by central planning, called the Holodomor. For 10 points, name this sort of disaster caused by a shortage of food."
      ],
      "answer": "famines <JB> {III}"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) William le Gros distinguished himself in battle during this conflict. A leader in this conflict escaped Oxford Castle by walking across the frozen River Isis. During this conflict, Thurstan of York helped crush the forces of David I at the Battle of the Standard. The Treaty of (20 pts)",
        "Wallingford was signed at the end of this conflict, which began after a ship carrying William Adelin sunk near the port of Barfleur. (10 pts)",
        "Stephen of Blois took power during this period upon the death of Henry I, subsuming the rightful heiress Empress Matilda. For 10 points, name this period of unrest in early 12th century England."
      ],
      "answer": "The Anarchy <CKM> {III}"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) For decades, the only English-language biography of this woman was Mary Main's The Woman with the Whip, which fiercely criticized her. This woman began wearing a black lace gown by Christian Dior in public after a trip in which she was greeted by Francisco Franco and snubbed by King (20 pts)",
        "George VI of Britain. This woman, who was accused of siphoning funds to a Swiss Bank from her namesake charitable \"Foundation,\" went on a (10 pts)",
        "\"Rainbow Tour\" of European capitals to raise support for her Justicialist husband. For 10 points, name this first wife and First Lady of Argentine dictator Juan Perón."
      ],
      "answer": "Eva Perón <MJ> {III}"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) Discussions of this artwork and of Emily Dickinson bookend and subtitle the aesthetics study Sexual Personae by literary critic Camille Paglia. This sculpture has been displayed in Germany since its 1912 unearthing by Ludwig Borchardt of the German Oriental Company. The subject of this limestone sculpture, whose left eye is now (20 pts)",
        "missing its pupil, wears a flat-topped blue crown indicating her status as a (10 pts)",
        "royal wife in Amarna. For 10 points, name this ancient Egyptian sculpture of the head, and chest of the queen of Pharaoh Akhenaten."
      ],
      "answer": "portrait bust of Nefertiti <MJ> {III}"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This monarch allied with an English king via the Treaty of Abernathy. A correction made by Cardinal Placentius prompted this king to snap \"I am the King of the Romans and above grammar!\" This monarch founded the Order of the Dragon after narrowly escaping capture when his crusade against (20 pts)",
        "Bayezid the Thunderbolt was defeated at Nicopolis. This king called a meeting which ended the Western Schism by electing (10 pts)",
        "Martin V, the Council of Constance. For 10 points, name this Holy Roman Emperor from the House of Luxembourg who shared his name with three later kings of Poland."
      ],
      "answer": "Sigismund of Luxembourg <JB> {III} 2015 National History Bowl High School Championships Round 14"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) The melody of this piece’s fifth movement was recycled from its composer’s Fête des belles eaux. This piece’s third movement was a solo for Henri Akoka in which the title creatures are “our desire… for jubilant Songs,” “Abyss of the birds.” Karl-Albert Brüll furnished three of the instruments for this piece’s first performance, and subsequently forged a stamp out of a potato to help (20 pts)",
        "free its performers. “Liturgy of Crystal” opens this 1941 eight-movement work which was composed in the (10 pts)",
        "Stalag VIII-A prisoner of war camp. For 10 points, what piece for violin, cello, piano, and clarinet was written by Olivier Messiaen?"
      ],
      "answer": "Quartet For the End Of Time <CW> {III}"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) The Meriam Report severely criticized the implementation of this law. Commissioner John Collier worked to repeal this law, which he believed did not help the people it applied to. The Burke Act adjusted this law to make it more difficult to become (20 pts)",
        "citizens. Henry Teller said this law created \"vagabonds\" in the name of humanity. This law did not apply to many portions of the (10 pts)",
        "Oklahoma Territory and it gave 160 acres to a head of an individual family, not tribe. For 10 points, name this pro-assimilation 1887 law that allotted land to American Indians."
      ],
      "answer": "Dawes Severalty Act of 1887 <MC> {III}"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) A British operation to reconstruct and analyze these objects was nicknamed Project Big Ben. La Coupole, a site in France, once housed these objects. One of these objects was recovered from Bäckebo County in Sweden. A facility producing them was targeted in Operation (20 pts)",
        "Hydra. These objects, which were primarily designed at the Peenemünde Army Research Center by Wernher (10 pts)",
        "von Braun, were used against Antwerp and London in the late phases of World War II. For 10 points, name these military projectiles launched by Nazi Germany in conjunction with V-1's."
      ],
      "answer": "V-2 rockets <KG> {III}"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) The contract that allowed this scandal to occur was signed by Herbert Hoxie. This scandal broke when Henry Simpson McComb leaked word to the newspaper New York Sun. George Francis Train and Thomas Durant created the company at the center of this scandal. In this scandal, (20 pts)",
        "Oakes Ames handed out shares for the namesake company, which implicated politicians such as James G. (10 pts)",
        "Blaine and then-Vice President Schuyler Colfax. For 10 points, name this scandal during Grant's presidency that involved the construction of the Union Pacific Railroad."
      ],
      "answer": "Credit Mobilier scandal <JL>"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) Columbia University's offer to this man of an endowed chair was cancelled due to mass student protests. This Cabinet member punished a subordinate for writing the Blood Telegram that questioned \"the suppression of democracy.\" Two members of the Nobel Committee resigned to protest the awarding of a Peace Prize to this (20 pts)",
        "American diplomat for the Paris Peace Accords. Le Duc Tho refused the Nobel he (10 pts)",
        "shared with this man for negotiating the Vietnam cease-fire. For 10 points, name this author of On China, a German-born Secretary of State for both Richard Nixon and Gerald Ford."
      ],
      "answer": "Henry Kissinger <MC> {III} 2015 National History Bowl High School Championships Round 14"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This event's subject proposed that he should be given free meals after finding out that a vote’s results were 280 to 220. One account of this event includes a digression about the rendition of Leon of Salamis, and begins with a story about how its subject was told by the Pythia that there were none (20 pts)",
        "wiser than he. Meletus questioned this event's central subject, who compared his city to a sluggish horse and himself to a (10 pts)",
        "gadfly. Its subject's defense against accusations of \"corrupting the youth\" is depicted in the Apology. For 10 points, identify this event in which an Athenian philosopher was sentenced to drink hemlock."
      ],
      "answer": "the trial of Socrates <KG> {III}"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) Activist Ray Robinson disappeared during an occupation of this location. James W. Forsyth's men controversially received twenty Medals of Honor for actions at this location. Marlon Brando's visit to this location led him to refuse his Best Actor Oscar for The (20 pts)",
        "Godfather. It’s not Alcatraz, but in 1973, this location was occupied by members of the American (10 pts)",
        "Indian Movement. An earlier incident at this location reacted to the sudden popularity of the Ghost Dance movement. For 10 points, name this location on the Pine Ridge Indian Reservation, where an 1890 massacre of Lakotas took place."
      ],
      "answer": "Wounded Knee <KG> {III}"
    }
  ]
}